DenysPotapov

PHP developer

contact

+38 050 330-20-57
Sidenys.potapov
in denyspotapov
denys.potapov@gmail.com

PHP skills

Phalcon, Silex, MySQL, PHPUnit, codeception, composer, TravisCI

front end skills

JavaScript, AngularJs HTML, CSS (SCSS), grunt

other skills

git, python, go

languages

bilingual Ukrainian/Russian intermediate English basic German

profile

I am a developer with over 9 years experience working on a variety of projects from conception to delivery. I am conversant in a wide range of technologies, now focused on PHP web development, follow the latest industry trends with great interest (OOP, PSR, SCSS, HTML5). My approach is methodical but creative. I am comfortable working either independently or as part of a team.

education

2002–2008 M.Sc. degree in Computer Science NTUU 'KPI'

Specialization in computer systems and robotics

experience

2012—2015	barzo.com.ua Creating and launching a start-up company. Developing from the ground e-commerce platform (PHP, MySql, HTML, SCSS). Working with and managing team of 3 freelancers.
2012—Present	Qport Creating a large network of digital signage systems (biggest project with 8000 screens). Integrating ERP system in retail stores (15 stores).
2009—2012	Qport Developing interactive screens software (python). Developing an ERP system for retail stores (1c ERP).
2008—2009	Physics-technological institute Development and integration of foundry process modeling system (Object Pascal) for perspective developments department institute of metals and alloys of the National academy of science of Ukraine
2005—2007	Proling Office Development of machine translation system ProlingOffice (C#) and it's online version (ASP.NET)

awards

June 2016	Ukraine Dev Challenge JS Front-end developer	3 rd place
November 2015	EU Web Challenge Back end development	1 st place
	Codingame oDesk Contest python developers	5 th place



advanced PHP back end development

• Modern PHP frameworks (Phalcon, Silex);

• SQL (MySQL, PDO);

• Code testing (PHPUnit, codeception);

• Continuous integration (composer, TravisCI);

• Version control systems (git, git-flow).

intermediate front end development

JavaScript, AngularJs, HTML, CSS (SCSS), grunt

basic **python, go**

languages

native Russian/Ukrainian

intermediate **English** conversationally fluent

basic German basic words and phrases only

community

blogging habrahabr.ru

Top-100 author in biggest Russian-speaking IT community

speaking IT conferences

Taking part in local IT conferences as visor and speaker. ('Object Calis-

thenics in php' at WebCamp Developer Day on youtube).

open source PHP password generator library

Library has 24 stars on github and more then 30 download on packagist

interests

volunteer Running a code club

Code-club in Kyiv is a part of network of volunteer-led after school cod-

ing clubs for children aged 9-11

running